所以回到我们的应用程序
so coming back to our app
我们想回应每个
we want to respond with each
裸名并输入 html 列表项
bare name and type in an html list item
是的，要做到这一点，我们需要绘制这些裸击的地图
yeah and to do that we'll need to map these bare struck
进入这些列表项
into these list items
所以我们知道我们需要做什么
so we know what we need to do
所以我们可以摆脱我们在那里做的事情
so we can get rid of our to do there
我要在这里建立一个管道
and I'm going to set up a pipeline here
我们将列出熊的名单
we'll take our list of bears
然后我们将它通过管道传送到 em
and then we're going to pipe it into em
地图记得
map remember
map 的第一个参数是该列表
the first argument to map is that list
所以这将通过管道输入
so that's going to be piped in
从左边
from the left
那么第二个参数是一个函数
then the second argument is a functions
我们将在这里使用匿名函数
we're going to use an anonymous function here
它会有一个参数，我们称之为 b
it's going to have an argument which we'll call b
代表熊
that represents the bear
然后是函数体
and then the body of the function
我们只是要连接一些字符串
we're just going to concatenate some strings
我们将有一个 li
we're going to have an li
然后插入到那个
and then interpolate into that
熊的名字
the bear's name
放一个破折号，然后我们将插入熊类型
put a dash and then we'll interpolate the bears type
然后我们就关闭li
and then we'll just close off the li
然后我经常忘记这一点，但你需要结束
and then I often forget this but you need to end
那个匿名函数
that anonymous function
所以这会给我们一个字符串列表
so that's going to give us a list of strings
这些盟友
these allies
但我们希望它们在最后放在一个大字符串中
but we want them in one big string at the end
所以我要使用
so I'm going to use
时间
em
加入，这将加入项目列表
join and that's going to join the list of items
这里的这些东西是字符串
these things here which are strings
变成一个字符串本身
into a string itself
它只是一长串
it's just going to be one long string
和里面的所有盟友
with all the allies inside
鉴于这将返回一串项目
of it so given that this returns a string of items
我要改变这个
I'm going to change this from
熊，因为这些不再是熊市了
bears because these aren't bear struck anymore
只是项目
to just items
然后在这里而不是有这些硬涂层
and then down here instead of having these hard coated
我们将在那里插入项目
we'll interpolate the items in there
所以我有个主意
so I have an idea
让我们展示所有的灰熊
let's just show all the grizzly bears
我们知道怎么做
and we know how to do that
我们可以使用过滤功能
we can use the filter function
是的，我们将在此处向管道添加一个步骤
yeah we'll just add a step to the pipeline right here
在我们得到熊的名单之后
after we get the list of bears
我们称酶过滤器
we'll call enzyme filter
该功能将采取
the function is going to take
将再次成为熊的争论
an argument which is going to be a bear again
然后是函数体
and then the body of the function
我们说 b 型等于 grizzly
we say b type equals grizzly
这将返回 true 或 false
that will return true or false
取决于类型是否为灰熊
depending on if the type is grizzly or not
这正是过滤器想要的
which is exactly what filter wants
如果它返回 true
and if it returns true
那么那只熊将在列表中
then that bear is going to be in the list
然后最后的接触让我们使用
and then for the final touch let's use
排序以按字母顺序排列名称
sort to put the names in alphabetical order
好吧，我们会在过滤后立即执行此操作
well we'll do that right after filter
所以只需在我们的管道中添加另一个步骤
so just add another step to our pipeline
现在我们给 sort 的函数有两个参数
now the function we give sort takes two arguments
我要打电话给b一和b二
I'm going to call in b one and b two
然后身体我们可以只说 b 一个名字
and then the body we can just say b one name
小于中心等于 b 两个名称
less center equal to b two name
这将返回一个包含熊的列表
and this will return a list with the bears
按他们的名字排序
sorted by their name
按字母升序排列
in ascending alphabetical order
把它存起来
save that away
重新编译
give it a recompile
现在需要重新加载调查处理程序
now need to reload survey handler
这是生成的 ul 就在这里
and here's the generated ul right here
我们注意到我们首先有布鲁图斯
we notice we have brutus first
敏锐的第二个，疤面煞星是最后一个
keen 2nd and scarface is last
所以我们有正确的顺序
so we've got those in the right order
我们正在生成 ul
and we're generating the ul with
我们期待的盟友
the allies we expected
所以我们的索引动作用 html 响应
so we have our index action responding with html
当我们在做的时候
while we're at it
让我们继续改变这个节目
let's go ahead and change this show
在这里用带有熊名字的 h 回应
to respond here with an h one with the bear's name
所以我们要做的就是委托给野生动物
so what we'll do is we'll delegate over to wild things
那是我们的模块
that's our module
假设我们有一个名为 get Bear 的函数
and let's assume we have a function called get bear
我们可以传入一个id
and we can pass in an id
它会返回带有该 ID 的熊
and it'll return the bear with that id
然后在响应正文中
then in the response body
改变这个，这将是一个h
change this around this will be an h one
我们会说熊，我们会插值
and we'll say bear and we'll interpolate
熊 id 放一个冒号
bear id put a colon
熊点名称
bear dot name
那么我们只需要定义这个函数
then we just need to define this function over
而事情
and while things
我会把它放在下面的熊名单下面
I'll just put it down below list bears here
给自己一点空间
give myself a little bit of space
它会被称为到达那里
it's going to be called get there
它需要一个 id
and it takes an id
在里面我们可以使用 e 名词 find
and inside of there we can use e noun find
不久前我们看到了六
we saw that in six a little while ago
我们会
and we'll just
将返回的熊的列表传递给它
pass it the list of bears that are returned by
列表具有功能
the list bears function
然后我们会给它一个函数
and then we'll give it a function
从具有给定 id 的列表中选择熊
that selects the bear from that list with the given id
所以它会起作用
so it'll be function
带熊
taking a bear
如果熊的身份证
if the bear's id
等于我们想要的意大利面ID
equals the pasta id then we want
选择那个
to select that
所以这将返回
so this is going to return
具有匹配 ID 的熊
the bear that has the matching id
但是双等号
but the double equal sign
假设 id 参数是一个整数
assumes that the id argument is an integer
这意味着除整数以外的任何值
this means that any value other than an integer
不匹配这是一个很好的观点
won't match that's a great point
例如，如果我们传入的 id 是一个字符串
if we pass in the id is a string for example
那么这个比较是行不通的
then this comparison isn't going to work
有一种新方法可以解决这个问题
and there's a new way to fix this
我们可以使用一种叫做保护爪的东西
we can use something called a guard claws
强制执行此功能的期望
to enforce this functions expectation
id 参数是一个整数
that the id parameter is an integer
我们在函数头上这样做，我们说什么时候
we do that up here on the function head we say when
然后在长生不老药中有一个函数叫做
and then there's a function in the elixir called is
整数，我们就这样传入那个id
integer and we pass in that id just like that
所以现在这个函数子句只会匹配
so now this function clause will only match
如果该 id 是一个整数
if that id is an integer
所以如果我们把它保存起来
so if we save this away
然后我们重新编译
then we recompile
重新加载我们的处理程序
reload our handler
我们看到我们得到这个没有功能爪匹配
we see we get this no function claws matching
裸露一个
get bare one
但请注意，我们用字符串调用 get bare
but notice we're calling get bare with a string
注意其中一个的双引号
notice the double quotes there of one
并且没有与之匹配的功能爪
and there's no function claws that matches that
所以我们的警卫正在工作
so our guard is working
那么为什么用字符串调用露莓
so why is dewberry getting called with a string
回到我们的控制器中
well back over in our controller
如果我们看这里
if we look here
我们只是模式匹配一个 id
we're just pattern matching an id
然后把它传入
and then passing that in
如果我们回头看一下处理程序
and if we look back over and handler
我们在哪里拿起那个 id
where we're picking up that id
就在这儿
right here
好吧，我们只是
well we're just
使用该连接运算符进行模式匹配
pattern matching using that concatenation operator
并获得 id 这将是
and getting id which will be
放入地图的字符串
a string that gets put in the map
这是有道理的，因为 url 只是一个字符串
and that makes sense because the url is just a string
我们只是把它的 id 去掉
and we're just pulling the id off of it
所以我们可以
so we could
在节目中将 id 转换为整数
convert the id to an integer right here in the show
行动
action
但是我们必须在有 id 的任何地方都这样做
but then we'd have to do that everywhere we have an id
所以不如让我们安排一下
so instead let's arrange things
以便获取裸函数
so that the get bare function
可以处理整数或字符串的 id
can handle ids that are either integers or strings
为此，我们会回到这里
and to do that we'll come back over here
我们将向下滚动一点
we'll scroll down a little bit
我们将定义
and we'll define
另一个名为 get bear 的函数子句
another function clause called get bear
它需要一个 id
it'll take an id
然后我们想要这个
and then we want this
当 id 是字符串时要匹配的函数子句
function clause to match when id is a string
所以我们说什么时候
so we say when
是二进制记住字符串或长生不老药中的二进制文件
is binary remember strings or binaries in elixir
所以当 id 是二进制的
so when the id is binary
我们想要做的是拿那个id
what we want to do is take that id
我们将使用字符串到整数将其转换为整数
we'll convert it to an integer using string to integer
然后我们将通过管道传输该整数
and then we'll pipe that integer
进入
into
这在这里得到了裸露的功能
this get bare function right here
现在如果我们以这种方式保存它应该可以工作
now if we save this way it should work
侦察重新加载，果然现在它可以工作了
recon reload and sure enough now it works
所以当 id 是一个整数时调用这个子句
so this clause is called when id is an integer
当 id 是一个字符串时调用这个子句
and this clause is called when id is a string
现在我们有一些工作了
now we have something working
但我想清理一些代码回来
but I want to clean up some code back
在控制器中
over in the controller
就在这个管道中，这里是过滤器排序和映射
right in this pipeline here are filter sort and map
然后我们有这些匿名函数
then we have these anonymous functions
这真的很难阅读
it's just really difficult to read and
了解发生了什么
understand what's going on as
你只需扫描那个代码
you just kind of scan that code
所以让我们快速重构一下
so let's do a quick bit of refactoring
使其更具描述性
to make it more descriptive
使其更具可读性
make it more readable
好吧，这是一个开始的地方
well here's a place to start
这里的代码只是创建一个裸
this code right here is simply creating a bare
行项目，所以让我们做一个功能来做到这一点
line item so let's make a function that does that
并命名函数
and name the function
裸物品是个好主意
bare item that's a good idea
现在您可以将该功能放在一个新模块中
now you could put that function in a new module
例如，仅具有视图辅助功能
that just has view helper functions for example
但我们只是要把它放在裸控制器中
but we're just going to put it in bare controller
所以我会复制到这里
so I'll copy it out here
我要把它放在这里
I'm going to put it right up here
这将是一个私人功能
it's going to be a private function
称为熊项目
called bear item
它会带上一只熊
it's going to take in a bear
然后我只是要粘贴
and then I'm just going to paste in
生成我们的列表项的连接字符串
that concatenated string that generates our list item
所以现在退到地图上
so now back down in map
而不是在这里做这个
instead of doing this right here
我们就把它拿出来
we'll just take this out
我们可以调用传入b的bear item，这就是bear
and we can call bear item passing in b that's the bear
哦，我要记住这里
oh and I got to remember up here
因为我们称参数为熊
because we called the argument bear
这也将是熊
that's going to be bear as well
接下来让我们把这段代码放在一个名为 is grizzly 的函数中
next let's put this code in a function named is grizzly
是的，因为这没有
yeah and since this doesn't have
与生成 html 和
anything to do with generating html and
真的与网络无关
really nothing to do with the web at all
我将把它放在我们的裸模块中
I'm going to put this inside of our bare module
所以这次我就删掉这个
so I'll just cut this one out this time
那边
over and there
我们知道我们可以将函数添加到一个模块中
we know that we can add functions into a module that
有一个结构
has a structure
所以这个叫灰熊
so this one's going to be called is grizzly
给它一只熊
give it a bear
我得改一下
I gotta change that over
所以它只是一个小
so it's just a small
返回真假的谓词函数
predicate function that returns truer false
然后回到我们的控制器中，我们可以调用 Bear
then back over in our controller we can call bear
是灰熊
is grizzly
传入 b 并且因为
passing in b and since
这个函数存在于模块之外
this function lives outside of the module
我们需要在它前面加上模块名称
we need to prefix it with the module name
我还要给它起别名
and I'm also going to alias it
所以我可以把它称为裸露的
so I can refer to it just as bare
而且因为我们很顺利
and since we're on a roll
让我们把这个订购代码也放入一个函数中
let's put this ordering code into a function as well
好的，我会把它从那里拿走
okay I'll take that out of there
感觉应该在裸模块中
and that feels like it should be in the bare module
以及
as well
我们将按名称升序调用该函数
we'll call that function order ascending by name
需要两只熊，你想成为两只
takes two bears you want to be two
然后它只是进行比较
and then it just does the comparison
那么在这里我们可以调用熊
then here we can call bear
按名称发送订单
order sending by name
传入b一和b二
passing in b one and b two
是的，这当然更具可读性它是否有效
yeah that certainly is more readable does it work
确实如此
indeed it does
是真的
it's really
像这样的匿名函数很常见
common to have anonymous functions like this that take
一两个参数，然后通过
one or two arguments and then pass them through
命名函数
to named functions
是的，你注意到那些匿名函数
yeah you notice those anonymous functions
转身打电话
just turn around and call
命名函数
the named functions with
无论给了他们什么论据
whatever argument was given them
所以这需要一只蜜蜂
so this takes a bee
只是转身用蜜蜂叫它的灰熊
just turns around and calls its grizzly with a bee
你最终会一直这样做
and you end up doing this all the time
所以毫不奇怪，长生不老药提供了一条捷径
so no surprise elixir provides a shortcut
在前任让我们说我有
over an ex let's say I have
这个词组列表 狮子 老虎 熊 ult
this list of phrases lions tigers bears ult
而我们想要做的是
and what we want to do is
将它们映射到他们的短缺版本
map them to their shortage version
所以我们可以使用鸸鹋地图
so we can use emu map
给它短语
give it the phrases
我们将有一个函数来接收每个短语
and we'll have a function that takes each phrase
然后调用字符串模块的 upraise 函数
then calls the string module's upraise function
传递那个字符串
passing that string
我们得到所有用大写字母喊出的短语
and we get all the phrases shouted out in uppercase
所以这是同样的情况
so this is the same situation right
我们有一个功能
we have a function
这需要
that takes
x 它只是转身并调用名称函数
x and it just turns around and calls a name function
现在通过它 x 作为快捷方式
passing it x now for the shortcut
我们可以使用捕获运算符
we can use the capture operator
看起来像这样
it looks like this it's an ampersand
然后我们可以在这里结束
and then we can drop the end here
而不是
and instead of
x 因为有
x because there's
没有 x 因为不再有匿名函数
no x because there's no anonymous function anymore
我们可以使用 &amp; 号
we can use ampersand one
这将是第一个参数的占位符
which will be a placeholder for the first argument
如果我们有两个论点
and if we had two arguments
那么你会使用＆符号两个
then you would use ampersand two
依此类推，如果我们这样做
and so on so if we do this
我们得到相同的结果
what we get back to the same result
所以这
so this
和这样做完全一样，只是一个捷径
is exactly the same as doing this it's just a shortcut
你可以想到和号
you can think of the ampersand
作为包装命名函数
as wrapping the named function
在匿名函数中
in an anonymous function
这与我们在上一行中的相同
this same as we had on this previous line
传递给匿名函数的参数
arguments passed to the anonymous function
传递给命名函数
are passed on to the named function
所以现在我们知道如何让我们的代码更简洁了
so now we know how to make our code a bit more succinct
是的，从这里的过滤器开始，我们将把它去掉
yeah starting with filter here we'll just drop this out
使用捕获运算符 &amp; 符号
use the capture operator the ampersand
有一个论点
there's one argument
所以我们使用 &amp; 号
so we use ampersand one
然后放下结尾
and then drop the end
我们将跳过这里
we'll skip down here
放下这个我们可以捕捉到那个功能
drop this we can capture that function
与号一
ampersand one
好吧，然后这个有点有趣
all right and then this one's a little interesting
因为它需要 b 1 和 b 2 2 参数
because it takes b one and b 2 2 arguments
但没问题
but no problem
这只是变成了小鬼
this just turns into imp one
这是小鬼二
and this is imp two
所以这很酷
so this is pretty cool
更好的是它仍然有效
and better yet it still works
但等他们说
but wait as they say
还有更多是的
there's more yeah
这里还有一个小捷径
there's one more tiny shortcut here
而不是像那样传递＆符号
instead of passing in ampersand one like that
我们可以使用函数的名称是 grizzly
we can use the name of the function is grizzly
和艺术的功能是一个
and the arty that function which is one
这有一个呃两个
this has an er two
所以会有斜线两个，这个有一个
so there will be slash two and this has an er one
这将是一样的
and that'll work just the same
现在这种速记语法既美味又简洁，但它
now this shorthand syntax is tasty and succinct but it
也变得神秘
also becomes cryptic
如果它被过度使用
if it's overused
我不仅在你有的情况下使用它
I didn't only use it in cases where you have
一两个论据
one or two arguments
它不会掩盖代码的意图
and it doesn't obscure the intent of the code
所以我会像我们一样在这里使用速记语法
so I'd use the shorthand syntax here as we did
因为我仍然认为它的可读性很强
because I still think it's quite readable
并记住
and remember
清晰的代码总是比聪明的代码好
clear code is always better than clever code